# Eugene Gluhotorenko

# Senior Software Engineer, TechLead

Minsk, Belarus

#### **PROFILE**

Software engineer with 9+ years experience in IT, focus on frontend development and have background in .NET. Passionate about programming, software engineering, data visualization and especially about creating rich frontend apps. My spare time I spend on reading popular science books, sport, traveling and developing open source.

#### **EDUCATION**

## Belarusian University of Informatics and Radioelectronics

B.Sc | Computer Science, Network systems

#### **SKILLS**

JavaScript, TypeScript, React, MobX, Redux, styled-components, PixiJS, Webpack, HTML, CSS, Git, Chrome DevTools, AngularJS and a lot of other libraries and tools.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Software TechLead

CCDS | Oct 2019 → current

TypeScript React MobX Cornerstone.js DICOM Scrum / Agile

- Develop a viewer for visualization of medical data and ML model generated output
- Develop a platform for processing medical studies.

#### Senior Software Engineer

BGAMING / SoftSwiss | Apr 2018 → Oct 2019

TypeScript PixiJS WebGL React MobX styled-components Scrum / Agile

- Develop game engine for multi-platform 2D games.
- Performance optimisation
- Technical interviewing of new candidates

#### Senior Software Engineer

MintData | Aug 2016 → Mar 2018

TypeScript React MobX MobX State Tree

- Develop a visual programming platform for creating real-time applications based on spreadsheets and visual GUI builder.
- Technical interviewing of new candidates

CTDev | Oct 2013 → Aug 2016

[avaScript | Angular]S | Highchars | D3.js | Scrum / Agile

- Develop a news portal with recommendation engine for financial sector with a lot of data visualisation features: charts, graphs, markets statistics tables and etc.
- Technical interviewing of new candidates

## Senior Software Developer

EPAM Systems | Dec 2010 → Sep 2013



- Develop a platform for publishing financial apps
- HTML5 apps for the platform (Time series data charts, market/exchange data viewers and
- JavaScript API for third-party app developers.
- Develop back-end services.

#### **BLOG ARTICLES**

• How styled-components works: A deep dive under the hood Aug 2018

#### **LINKS**

• Home page: e.gluhotorenko.com

• Email: e.gluhotorenko@gmail.com

• Github: gevgeny

• Telegram: egluhotorenko

• LinkedIn: eugene-gluhotorenko